# **GREGORY GILES**

07929297214

greg.giles3@gmail.com

github.com/Gilo243

A highly motivated, versatile and ambitious data professional with a keen interest in data science and technology. Four years experience as digital reporting analyst team lead within IPG Mediabrands London, coupled with an upper second honours degree in Mathematics from the University of Sheffield, has given me a solid foundation in data analysis, reporting, statistics and in particular, problem solving through the rigorous interrogation of data. I have a passion for continuous self development and am always looking to expand my data analysis skillset through learning new analytical techniques and tools.

Having recently taken some time out to focus on my professional development, completing python bootcamp and intensive data science courses, I am now seeking my next challenge in which to use my proven analytical skillset. Committed to my own professional development, I am keen to undertake additional training to perform a new role to the best of my ability, ideally as part of a structured development programme.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Advanced Excel
- Python (incl. NumPy & Pandas)
- Machine Learning (inc. Scikit-learn)
- Power-Pivot & DAX
- Data Visualisation (incl. Seaborn & Tableau)
- · Adservers: DoubleClick, Atlas, Sizmek
- Experience with Google Analytics and Adobe Site Catalyst

### **EMPLOYMENT**

May 2014 - May 2016 IPG Mediabrands London Ad Ops Report Analyst Lead

Responsible for the day to day digital reporting across multiple agencies under the Mediabrands umbrella. Clients included some of the world's largest brands, such as Johnson & Johnson, Microsoft, Xbox, Exxon Mobil and Rockstar Games.

As lead of a team of 3 analysts, it was my role to oversee the creation and timely delivery of digital campaign insight reports. This entailed working closely with internal clients/media planner buyers to assess campaign KPI's, relay insights and influence necessary actions.

Provide training and support where needed in Microsoft Excel, PowerPivot and other analytical reporting platforms within the digital advertising industry. Created scripts in python to help automate data cleaning processes and speed up the reporting process.

April 2012 - May 2014 Universal McCann London Ad Ops Digital Analyst Leverage my analytical background and digital experience to translate complex results into clear insights and actions for decision makers.

Tasked with the creation and maintenance of campaign performance reports for multiple clients. These reports were built by wrangling together data from multiple sources - Adservers, Google Analytics, SiteCatalyst and offline data to name a few.

Other functions included adserving discrepancy analysis and adhoc 'deep dive' analysis projects into digital advertising areas of interest such as viewability and engagement.

### **EDUCATION** 2007-10

#### University of Sheffield - BSc Mathematics

(Upper second class honours)

Modules included:

- Complex Analysis
- Operations Research
- Financial Mathematics
- Combinatorics
- Codes & Cryptography

2005-07

#### **Tunbridge Wells Grammar School for Boys** (ALevels)

Maths (A) Physics (B) Psycology (C)

# **GREGORY GILES**

### **ADDITIONAL**

**Courses & Qualifications** 

Springboard Data Science Intensive - Mentoured Course

Complete Python - Bootcamp

Analytics Edge - Online

Dataquest.io (Data Scientist Track) - Online

Google Analytics Individual Qualification

### **PERSONAL SKILLS**

Analytically minded with a sharp attention to detail as evidenced through my qualifications and experience.

Comfortable in handling large amounts of data from disparate data sources and extracting valuable insights.

Confident and approachable team player with first class interpersonal and communication skills as evidenced through employment, team sports and volunteer work, both in the UK and overseas.

Methodical and reliable, I am able to manage my time effectively working to targets within strict deadlines, a skill honed from working 4 years at a busy advertising agency.

### **INTERESTS**

- Football
- Travelling
- Raspberry Pi
- Volunteering
- Reading
- Rock Climbing

### REFERENCES

Available on request